# TOMÁŠ PILAŘ

4 Gillies Close ♦ Cambridge, CB5 8ZD, United Kingdom +44 · 7531 · 784896 ♦ sir.integra@gmail.com

A friendly, competent and dedicated software engineer with experience in UEFI and Linux kernel drivers. Prefers to work with a good team, designing and delivering well crafted products. Spare time is filled with friends playing board games or live-action games, or learning more about the technologies he works with.

- "Rare Depictions of Homo Programmeris Systemus"

### EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

# Qualcomm Inc. (Nuvia acquisition)

June 2020 - Present

Senior Staff Software Engineer

Remote

- · Developed and maintained AP firmware for a novel SoC product
- · Designed and developed a custom inter-processor messaging framework with interesting features
- · Developed and maintained a QEMU virtual platform for a novel SoC product
- · Designed, implemented and maintained the packaging tools and CI framework for the firmware, virtual plaform and the infrastructure itself
- · Wrote and gave tutorials on development with Git, Gitlab and VS code

### Xilinx Inc. (Solarflare acquisition)

July 2019 - March 2020

Staff Software Engineer

Cambridge, UK

- · UEFI Technical Lead and Linux Driver Developer
- · Full ownership of the UEFI Project including design, development, test and CI
- · Mentored junior member of the UEFI team

#### **Solarflare Communications**

June 2017 - July 2019

Senior Software Engineer

Cambridge, UK

- · UEFI Driver and Linux Driver Developer
- · Developed industry contacts facilitating higher quality of the UEFI products in-house.
- · Tutored junior members of other teams to disseminate institutional knowledge
- · Collaborated cross-team to design specifications, implement features, develop OEM products, and debug complex issues.

### **Solarflare Communications**

June 2014 - June 2017

Software Engineer

 $Cambridge, \ UK$ 

- · Test Automation Engineer and Test Developer, Linux Driver Developer
- $\cdot$  Designed and implemented test cases for multiple products using asynchronous Python framework based on twisted
- · Pioneered in-house CI frameworks streamlining the development process
- · Thoroughly benchmarked the linux kernel driver using a custom-built tool
- · Created in-house test harness for product web-UI using the Selenium framework

### **EDUCATION**

# University of Warwick, UK

October 2010 - June 2014

PhD in Particle Physics

Thesis on analysing data from LHCb to extract Standard Model parameters

Transferrable Doctoral Skills Course

Long Term Attachment in CERN, Geneva (14 months)

# University of Warwick, UK

October 2006 - June 2010

MMathPhys (2.1), Thesis in Particle Physics

# BASG Milana Hodžu, Sučany, Slovak Republic

October 2001 - June 2006

A-level equivalent (AAAABB)

### TECHNICAL COMPETENCIES

Systems Programming (Linux & UEFI)

Test Development and Automation

Version Control

Database Design & Administration

C (8 years) C++ (2 years)

Python (10 years), Gitlab (3 years), Jenkins (2 years)

Git (8 years) and Mercurial (5 years)

T-SQL, mySQL, mariaDB

#### POSITIONS OF RESPONSIBILITY

**GAUSS Monte Carlo Simulation Group** 

Decay Files repository manager

EvtGen Development Group Development and technical support

LHCb UK Student Group

Convener

University of Warwick Computing Society

Co-President

October 2010 - June 2014 University of Warwick, UK

LHCb Collaboration, CERN

October 2011 - June 2014

June 2012 - December 2012 LHCb Collaboration, CERN

February 2007 - January 2009

University of Warwick, UK

#### OTHER SKILLS

Languages Slovak & Czech (Native), English (Bilingual), French (Intermediate)

Management Software JIRA, Bugzilla, Reviewboard, Slack, Confluence Methodology Agile development and Continuous Integration **Public Speaking** Experience chairing meetings (up to  $\sim 40$  people)

#### INTERESTS AND HOBBIES

#### **Professional**

Low-level programming (system software or firmware), solving complex problems Designing robust systems that last, leaving code in better shape, bringing hardware to life Imparting institutional knowledge

#### Personal

Games (board, computer, card, and live action), literature, theatre, musicals, travelling, swing dancing

# COMMUNICATIONS

**UEFI Plugfest** Autumn 2016 - 2019

Regular attendee on behalf of Solarflare Communications

Charm mixing in  $D^0 \to K_S \pi \pi$  at LHCb

https://cds.cern.ch/record/2008671?ln=en

June 2014 University of Warwick

Model-independent measurement of mixing parameters in  $D^0 \to K_S \pi \pi$  decays April 2016 http://link.springer.com/article/10.1007%2FJHEP04%282016%29033

Charm mixing and CP violation at LHCb

Journal of High Energy Physics

Large Hadron Collider Physics Conference

Barcelona, Spain

May 2013

Measuring charm mixing using a model-independent technique in  $D^0 o K_S hh$ 

Institute of Physics HEP Conference

April 2013 Liverpool, UK

REFERENCES

References available on request